ZOBAER AHMED

PO Box: 553, State University, Arkansas 72467 Mobile: +1-347-493-7139 zunnun09@gmail.com

② zobaerahmed.us in www.linkedin.com/in/zobaer-ahmed

Agriculture, Climate Change, Adaptation and Sustainability Data Researcher

Career Summary

Multidisciplinary professional. Key areas of interest and expertise include Climate and its Impact Assessment, Vulnerabilities and Risk Analysis, Climate Change Adaptation Strategies in Agriculture & Food Security, Human-Environment System Interactions, Rural Development, Environmental and Sustainable Development, Market Research & Strategy, Proposal Writing, Article Review & Editing, Monitoring & Evaluation and Project Management

Research Experience

Jan 2020 - Current Ph.D. Graduate Research Assistant

Arkansas State University (USA)

- Managing data collection, analysis and writing papers for publications
- Part-time teaching Bachelor level students
- Working with scientists (climate change adaptation in agriculture, vulnerability and food security)

Sep 2018 - May 2019 Visiting Research Fellow

Florence University (Italy)

- Facilitated as a guest lecturer in several workshops and seminars on research methods
- Directed climate change adaptation innovation works with water harvesting lab
- Collaborated in proposal writing and joint publication

Jan 2013 - Aug 2017 Assistant Manager (Monitoring and Research)

Friendship NGO (BGD)

- Supervised and managed 30+ projects in DRR, agriculture, food security & climate change adaptation
- Structured 20+ research proposals and concept notes (secured funding for 12 proposals)
- Developed 15+ project monitoring and evaluation guidelines, operation manuals, and innovative process manuals to improve operational outcomes

Mar 2016 - Sep 2017

2020 - Ongoing

2007 - 2012

Country Manager (Research, Strategy and Operation)

Premise Data (USA)

- Managed and supervised directly more than 3000+ users
- Controlled payments distribution of more than 0.5 million USD
- Escalated user issues and followed proper training procedure
- Developed 5+ in-depth training manuals and visuals for users

Education

Arkansas State University

GPA (Until Fall, 2020): 4.00/4.00

2017 - 2019

Joint International Master of Science in Rural Development (IMRD)

Ghent University, Humboldt University of Berlin and Pisa University

Credit Hour: 60, GPA: 3.61/4.00

2012 - 2014

Master of Science in Disaster (Climate Change) Management

University of Dhaka

Ph.D. in Environmental Sciences

Bachelor of Science in Agriculture

Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujibur Rahman Agricultural University

Credit Hour: 244, GPA: 3.47/4.00

Credit Hour: 60, GPA: 3.60/4.00

Computer Skills

Microsoft Office Suite, Outlook, Data Analytics Software (R-Studio, Base R, ArcGIS Pro, SPSS, Excel Solver), Mobile Based Data Solution, Basic UI, and UX designing, Communication (UserVoice, Slack, Trello, Intercom, Zoho, etc), Google Suite, Mendeley, Prezi.

Major Trainings and Certifications

- Measuring Climate Adaptation Success and Progress: Introduction to the Resilience Metrics (Graham Sustainability Institute)
- Case Study Certificate on Agriculture and Rural Transitions
- Research Internship Certificate at COSPE, Italy
- International Training Workshop on Monitoring and Evaluation (M&E) for Community Based Adaptation (CBA)
- Training Course on SPSS data analysis software for Professionals, Researchers, and Students
- Training Program on Community-Level Collapse Structure Search, Rescue, First Aid, and Fire Fighting Operation

Achievement and Awards

- Received funding for Ph.D. research from Arkansas State University (USA)
- Received European Commission Erasmus Mundus Scholarship 2017-2019 for Study MSc in International Rural Development
- Received Ghent University, Belgium Top-up grant 2017
- Telenor Youth Forum 2016 (Semi-Finalist- m-Donation system)
- Olympic Day Run Certificate 2008

Key Publications

- Work in Progress (Research Article): Climate Change Risk Perceptions May Drive Agricultural Technology Adoption in the Polder Areas of Bangladesh. (Southern Agricultural Economics Association: https://www.saea.org/)
- Joint Work in Progress (Research Article): Identifying Drivers of NRCS Conservation Cost-Share Program Participation in Arkansas
- Recently submitted (Research Article): Climate Change Risk Perceptions and Agricultural Adaptation Strategies in Vulnerable Riverine Char Islands of Bangladesh (Land Use Policy Journal: https://www.journals.elsevier.com/land-use-policy)
- Recently submitted (Book Chapter): Agriculture in Riverine Chars of Northern Bangladesh: Vulnerabilities to Climate Change and Community Based Adaptation (https://link.springer.com/)
- Pattern Recognition of Rainfall Using Wavelet Transform in Bangladesh (http://www.scirp.org/Journal/PaperInformation.aspx? PaperID=82469)
- Impact of Climate Change on Food Security in Bangladesh (https://www.omicsonline.org/open-access/impact-of-climate-change-onfood-security-in-bangladesh-2157-7463-1000306.pdf)
- Case Study: Mainstreaming Disaster Risk Reduction into the Construction Sector in Bangladesh (http://www.irdrinternational.org/2017/05/12/co-designing-disaster-risk-reduction-solutions-towards-participatory-action-andcommunication-in-science-technology-and-academia/)

Dissertations

- 1st Master's thesis: Food Security, Climate Change Experience and Adaptation Strategies for Agriculture in Southern Patuakhali of Bangladesh
- 2nd Master's thesis: Community-based climate change adaptation in agriculture and food security status of hazard-prone rural riverine char areas in Bangladesh

References

References Available Upon Request



Created with **TVisualCV**